Mobile Suit
Rage on! Rage on! Rage on! Gundam!
Moeagare! Moeagare! Moeagare GANDAMU!
Kimi yo hashire
You must run forth!
Mada ikari ni moeru toshi ga aru nara...
If you are still burning with furious rage...
Kyodai na teki o
You must fight the towering foe!
Uteyo! Uteyo! Uteyo!
Fight! Fight! Fight!
Seigi no ikari o butsukero GANDAMU
Bring to bear the rage of justice, Gundam
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Yomigaeru! Yomigaeru!
Rise once more! Rise once more!
Yomigaeru GANDAMU!
Rise once more! Gundam!
Kimi yo tsukame
You must seize the power!
Ginga e mukatte tobeyo GANDAMU
Fly toward the galaxy, Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
A half-century has passed since humanity began moving...
...its burgeoning population into space.
These gigantic space colonies orbiting the Earth...
...became a second home to humanity...
...where people were born and raised...
...and where they died.
It is the year 0079 of the Universal Century.
The colonies of Side 3 proclaimed themselves
the Principality of Zeon.
It launched a war of independence
against the Earth Federation.
During this war, the Principality of Zeon
and the Federation...
...caused the deaths
of half the total population.
Humanity was horrified by its own actions.
Fly, Gundam!
Group 3. Your meals are ready.
Oh, that's right! Amuro's got to eat too!
Amuro! It's time to eat!
Amuro?
A-mu-ro...!
What's wrong?
Nothing...
Do you have a fever?
No.
If you're tired, do you want to skip the meal?
I haven't had a decent night's sleep
since leaving Side 7.
Even when I have the time, I can't sleep.
Do you want to talk to Ms. Sayla about it?
Isn't she a medical student?
Quit bugging me!
Cut it out! This isn't like you, Amuro!
It's a lot less like me
to fight in a mobile suit!
This war's killed practically every adult!
Old people and kids younger than you have to fight!
It's the same for Zeon
and the Federation. Isn't it?
Stop biting your nails. It's a bad habit.
The Federation is using us as a decoy.
Decoy?
The Federation is developing
even newer weapons.
We're supposed to distract the enemy
until they're finished.
Just a decoy. That's all we are.
You're over-thinking things. You should rest.
I'll set aside your meal.
What? No contact yet?
Incoming transmission.
It's probably from General HQ.
Good.
This is White Base...
This is Defense HQ.
Use decryption circuit Alpha Gain.
Alpha Gain. Roger.
It says the White Base is to break through
enemy lines and escape to the sea.
That's all.
They're not coming to help us?
Hey! Can't we talk to them?
With General HQ?
It's impossible.
We're in Zeon territory,
and even coded transmissions aren't safe.
What could the generals be thinking?
They don't know what goes on in the field!
Mr. Tamura. The meals for the elderly...?
Well, of course there's no way
for us to prove it...
That's slander!
How could I have time to eat well
when I'm so busy cooking?!
But you do look suspiciously healthy.
Why, you!
All right, I'll ask you straight out.
Why is it that only Amuro and Ryu
get bigger portions?
Mr. Bright's orders!
We're to treat them like regular pilots!
Thank you for the meal!
We're fighting too, you know.
A soldier's calorie intake is adjusted according to his workload!
Don't quarrel in here, Mr. Kai.
Talk to Mr. Bright or Lt. Reed.
Yeah, right.
Amuro!
I'll give you something nice!
Here!
Good luck!
Kikka...
Don't tell anyone else.
Right.
We're getting low on ammunition.
It won't last us through another battle.
I know. That's why I'm thinking
of how we can get through this...
It's easy if all you want to do
is survive, Bright.
You must be kidding.
We can abandon the White Base.
Lt. Reed?!
Sorry about before.
Don't worry about it.
Have some of mine.
Are you sure? Thank you.
Amuro!
You need to eat properly!
Then don't make me eat in a place like this.
Amuro...!
Then what was it all for...?
All of our fighting up until now.
It wasn't in vain.
Everyone here has grown more confident
they can carry on in this war.
Bright! All repairs to damaged areas
have been completed.
Where's Hayato and Sayla?
They're on gun maintenance.
I'll send out a patrol.
Amuro! I'm sending you out on patrol.
Report to the bridge!
What are you doing? Hurry!
Amuro! Hurry!
Why stir things up by sending out a patrol?
What?!
Besides, you're always sending me out
to fight. I'm sick of it!
Amuro...
Amuro's exhausted.
And we rely on him too much.
Hayato and I will go on patrol.
Let the computer fly it!
Yes, sir! That's what I'm trying to do!
Set the computer to automatically
follow my plane.
Roger!
There!
Garma, surely there's no need
for you to go personally. Right?
I have to consider what my sister
might think of me.
As you have no family,
you wouldn't understand my problems.
All hands, prepare for sortie!
What's wrong?
Enemy fighters, sir!
What?!
Garma! Cancel the sortie. Get back!
I'm going now, and I'll shoot them down.
Come back, Garma.
Mr. Ryu! Why aren't we attacking?
After all, we managed to find the Gaw!
We'd be able to attack the Gaw
if we had another six Core Fighters!
This image was from 30 seconds ago.
It's just a patrol.
It could mean the Trojan Horse is
getting impatient.
Getting impatient?
It's the first patrol the Trojan Horse
has sent out.
They must have some weakness.
That's why they're checking our movements.
I see.
Instead of attacking the small fry,
we should go for the real prize.
All right! Pursue the enemy patrol!
Good.
Transfer the Core Fighters to the Guncannon
and Guntank immediately!
Back into the coffin.
I'll head up. Take over here, Mr. Ryu.
I'm not used to this, so help me out.
Sure!
I thought maybe you'd understand,
Fraw Bow.
Well, I don't.
Even Mr. Kai's in the Guncannon.
They're all prepared to fight.
They'll eventually get sick of it.
It's different for me.
I've been forced to go out, over and over.
What is it, Fraw Bow?
Amuro's not up to it.
He says he doesn't want to fight.
What?!
Bright...
Amuro! Listen! You have to sortie!
Can you guarantee
I'll be able to sleep soundly afterwards?
Guarantee?!
Amuro...
I can't help how I feel.
If you didn't go out and fight for us...
I would've been dead long ago.
It's the same for me, too!
But... I'm tired of being scared!
Whew! A safe landing.
All clear, Kai!
All right.
My, my, is this all the fighting strength
we've got? Eh, Mr. Bright?
The Gundam will be joining you soon.
Have confidence in our fighting strength.
All right?
Yeah, yeah. You sure know how
to make me feel better, Ms. Sayla.
Amuro!
Why don't you try to fulfill your duty?
Why are you fighting, Mr. Bright?
We don't have time for philosophy!
Stand up, you!
Please stop.
If you want to deploy the Gundam so badly...
...you should go out in it yourself!
What?!
I'd do it if I could!
I don't need to be told by you!
I shouldn't have to do it, just because I can.
You... You hit me...
Mr. Bright!
Why shouldn't I hit you?
Fine! Go ahead and throw your tantrums.
Maybe you'll feel better then!
D-Do you really think
I'm such a petty person?!
Mobile Suit
Reinforcements from the left flank!
Ryu, be careful!
All right! Kai, don't go too far ahead
and get shot down!
Hayato, we're getting low on ammo!
Aim well!
Roger!
Char, can you hear me?
I know why the Trojan Horse is impatient.
Well, that's good. So what's the reason?
Please, tell me.
It's the mobile suit.
There are two land-combat types out,
but not the one in question.
I suspect they can't deploy it.
Don't interfere. Just watch, Char.
I'm going to bring them down!
I'm looking forward to seeing
your splendid attack.
That's a hit!
Concentrate your fire on the left engine!
Guncannon, Guntank. Enemy is firing
on port side. Requesting cover.
There they are.
You bastards...!
D-Damn!
You hit me again!
Not even my father ever hit me!
That's why you're such a spoiled brat!
Show me a real man
who's grown up without being hit once!
That's it! I refuse to go on!
I'll never get in the Gundam again!
Amuro! That's enough!
Get a hold of yourself!
Don't be so pathetic, Amuro!
I'm off to the bridge.
Amuro, right now
you're no better than an insect.
Given your great talent...
...I thought you'd be able to surpass Char.
I'm disappointed.
Char...?
Mr. Bright.
Mr. Bright!
Amuro, there's a manual on
how to operate the Gundam, right?
What?
I'll pilot the Gundam.
I hate people who won't take pride
in what they can do!
Amuro, if you can't proudly declare that
you protected the White Base until now...
...you're not a real man!
I...
Fraw Bow...
There's no way you can pilot the Gundam.
Amuro...
I hate to say this...
...but I guess I am a man.
Amuro. Are you going? Amuro.
Damn that Char!
Mr. Ryu, the enemy's only firing
at the White Base!
Rotate to the right!
All right!
I only hit one?!
We can't shoot down fighters
without anti-aircraft weapons!
Beebe, don't waste time on the small fry.
Just the Trojan Horse.
Just aim for the Trojan Horse's engines.
Yes, Captain!
Right! Follow me!
Amuro! The Dopps are concentrating fire
on the White Base's port side engine.
You can handle an anti-air combat, right?
Amuro.
Yes. I'd like to try a new battle tactic.
I need the Guntank and Guncannon
to cover me.
I'll pass it on.
We're counting on you.
You know, I'm quite impressed by
Captain Garma's attacks.
He didn't get to be a captain
merely because of his father.
Lt. Commander, is this all right?
Just to watch like this?
I think so.
He said he'd request assistance
if he needs it.
If we interfere without his asking,
it'll hurt his pride... and we'll get in trouble.
We can still use the radio
at this distance, right?
Yes, sir. The Minovsky particle density
hasn't changed...
...but we should at least get audio.
That's fine then.
I don't want to get scolded by Garma either.
So you've come out, damned mobile suit.
But it is a ground combat weapon after all.
Beebe squadron, attack the mobile suit!
Don't underestimate me.
The Gundam does have jumping abilities,
and rocket nozzles.
The mobile suit is flying!
There!
1...!
Amuro...!
The Gundam is engaged in aerial combat.
What?!
Incredible!
Cancel the radio restriction! Sayla!
Instruct the Guntank and Guncannon...
...to cover the Gundam
so he can land without being fired upon.
Yes, sir!
Guntank, Guncannon.
Can you see the Gundam?
I know.
That Amuro is amazing!
Hayato! Let's cover him!
Roger that!
We just have to keep the Dopps
at high altitude, right?!
I'm not letting the Dopps any closer!
8... 5... 2... 0...!
The mobile suit is jumping!
No, it's practically flying!
The Federation has built
an unbelievable mobile suit.
3...
Mr. Bright!
Look at the way Amuro's fighting!
Yeah, that's terrific. Even when he was
sulking, he was still thinking how to fight.
That's right!
Amuro, you've gotten stronger.
Bastard!
6... and the next will be 7...
7...!
That must be the squadron leader.
You monster! Go down! Go down!
T-This is...
He's good...!
Do you read, Gaw? It's me!
I'll lure the mobile suit
away from the Trojan Horse.
Once it's within the Gaw's range,
shoot the mobile suit down!
You're not getting away!
He doesn't know he's entering
the Gaw's beam cannon range.
Gaw! Fire! At the mobile suit!
Can't you hear me?!
Gaw! It's me! It's Garma!
What's going on?
I'm sure it's transmitting on my end.
Damn!
Oh, no!
A Federation transport?!
You, in the mobile suit. Do you read me?
If you cross the mountains,
the Gaw will get you.
Get back to White Base!
Who is that?!
She seems to know everything, but...!
With all the dirt on this plug, it's no wonder
radio communications were faulty.
Chief Engineer, you can expect
disciplinary action!
And you're no better.
I concur.
I'm sure you saw the action
on the laser scope.
Even without any contact from me,
you should have taken some measures.
That's because I didn't want
to hurt your pride.
My pride?
You told me to just watch.
And with your skills, Garma...
...I had faith that you'd be able to
deal with such minor damage.
Well, of course.
The unfortunate thing is...
...when we tried to shoot down
the enemy transport...
...you were in its direct path, Garma.
So we couldn't fire.
Sorry.
It's all right.
As long as you understand, Char.
All Salamis crew including Lt. Reed...
...plus the sick and injured refugees.
We're taking 35 people in total.
As for the White Base and the mobile suits...
...we have no new orders,
so they'll remain as is.
Furthermore, I request copies
of your combat records...
...under orders from General Revil.
But Lt. Matilda, I don't understand.
Why are they keeping us
with the ship as is?
I don't know.
General Revil says if the White Base
can continue to fight as it has...
...it's the same as any regular forces.
The Federation's facing some tough times.
Even I...
...have come this far only
at General Revil's request.
It has nothing to do with General HQ.
And? Will we be resupplied again?
Well, if you can escape from Zeon airspace.
In any case...
Remember that some in the Federation
have not abandoned you.
Ms. Matilda...
Without your fighting skills,
we would be dead too.
Thank you.
You may be some kind of esper.
N-No way, not me...
Good luck.
Yes, ma'am.
Matilda departs, leaving only
a fleeting hint of fragrance.
For Amuro...
...this is his first experience
of the scent of a woman.
Garma can't fail to destroy
the White Base...
...as he feels his romance with Icelina
hinges upon it.
Garma Zabi launches his final assault.
While Amuro and crew
battle terror in the dark...
...Char's plot unfolds,
sealing Garma's fate.
Mobile Suit Gundam. Next episode...
Garma's Fate.
Next Time
Garma's Fate
Will you be able to survive?
Amuro, do not look back
The star shining far off in space...
Amuro, it's your homeland where you were born
Do you remember the days of your childhood?
The morning when you woke up in warmth?
Amuro, do not look back, Amuro...
A man must hide his tears, hide his tears
Only look to tomorrow, to tomorrow forever...